Jorge Maestro

Product designer · UX/UI · Architect

Diving deeper into UX after over 7 years of experience in fields such as design, marketing & architecture; key strategical elements in relation to contributing and sharing value as a good Product Designer. Along with the hard skills acquired; owning a strong sense of aesthetics, being a good communicator and a spirited team-builder are considered the greater strengths that I have.



Contact

JM https://jorgemaestro.github.io/portfolio/

- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/jorge-maestro/
- jorgemaestroaguilera@gmail.com
- +34 617 981 978

Last UX/UI Projects

- Fakulty | Creating a problem Statement
- Sustainable Broker | Finances
- Storytel | App | Adding a New feature
- Barkonsult | e-commerce Redesign

Software

Figma, Visual Studio, Zeroheight, InVision, Zeplin, AutoCad, 3DSMax, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Microsoft Office, Notion.

Skills

UX Research, Interviews & Surveys, Journey Mapping, Information Architecture, Prototyping, Visual Design, HTML, CSS, Agile.

Languages

Spanish - Native

English - Fluent

French - Beginner

Other works

https://www.vittoriachess.com/

Professional experience

Architect & Project Manager | 2021 - Current | Madrid, Spain

Freelance | Architecture, Design & Business Development

- Founder of NAIA design boutique in Doha, Qatar. Carrying out 6 full projects.
- Drive the whole design process, from problem to solution space delivering 3 full projects up to date.
- Coordinate execution times in budget with client and subcontractors meeting deadlines 100% of the times.
- Lead, negotiate and manage the interaction of jobs on the site.
- Head of Design | Interior Design & Architecture | 2018 2021 | Doha, Qatar Fosc Studio | Architecture & Interior Design
 - Design around customer needs. Incorporating insights, business requirements, and technical constraints. Increasing sales in more than 120% in less than a year.
 - Communication, coordination and management of consultants, contractors, clients, regulatory agencies and approving bodies to meet overall project objectives.
 - Key Account manager of an over 50 client's portfolio.
 - Led a 7 people team and delivered over 35 projects.

Junior Architect & Project Manager | 2018 | Madrid, Spain

Archer Architecture | Design & Build

- Generate detailed 2D and 3D models to develop all parts of the design process.
- Collaborate with other designers and engineers to propose solutions for the functionality and visuals ensuring product consistency and feasibility.

Head of Animations & Styles | 2016 - 2018 | Warsaw, Poland

PrezArt | Marketing & Communication

- Present and defend to over 30 clients the different design solutions proposed.
- Seek out solutions from problems in developing animations for stakeholders.
- Plan, lead and execute the design and style, from concept and prototype to high-fidelity product submitting over 25 projects yearly.

Education

UX/UI Design Full Time Bootcamp

Ironhack | 2022 | Madrid, Spain

MBA and Digital Marketing specialization

The Power Business School | 2021 - 2022 | Madrid, Spain

Erasmus Program

Poznan University of Technology | 2013 - 2014 | Poznan, Poland

Bachelor's degree in Architecture

UPSAM | 2008 - 2014 | Madrid, Spain